Welcome, in the last lecture, we added in this climb idle animation and this climb drop
欢迎，在上一次讲座中，我们加入了这个爬升空闲动画和这个爬升下降的
animation.
动画。
Now, our character can transition into the climb state with the correct idle animation
现在，我们的角色可以通过正确的空闲动画过渡到爬升状态
and we can exit the climb state with the correct exiting animation.
我们可以用正确的退出动画退出爬升状态。
And all's left there to do is to add in the locomotion for climbing when we are moving.
剩下要做的就是在我们移动的时候为爬升添加运动。
And same as always, I like to take care of the coding part first.
和往常一样，我喜欢先处理好编码的部分。
So close my project and go to my custom moving component.
所以关闭我的项目，进入我的自定义移动组件。
So same as our ground locomotion, we will get hold of the climb speed in order to play
和我们的地面运动一样，我们将掌握爬升速度，以便播放
the correct animation.
正确的动画。
And for that, I'm going to create a getter directly inside of this class.
为此，我将在这个类中直接创建一个getter。
So scroll down inside of this public section.
所以向下滚动这个公共部分。
So this function is going to return an F vector.
所以这个函数将返回一个F向量。
I'm going to call this get unrotated climb velocity.
我将调用这个获取未旋转的爬升速度。
And it's going to be const.
它将是一个常数。
So the climbing velocity has already been rotated, in order to have the correct one,
所以爬升速度已经被旋转过了，为了得到正确的爬升速度、
we will need to rotate it back.
我们将需要把它旋转回来。
So I'm going to create a function definition and go to the CPP file.
所以我将创建一个函数定义并进入CPP文件。
I'm going to place the function below this on climb montage ended.
我将把这个函数放在攀登蒙太奇的下面，结束。
And to unrotate a vector, we will need to access a function inside of Kitsima math library.
为了解除矢量的旋转，我们需要访问Kitsima数学库中的一个函数。
And I'm going to steal the include from the CPP file of nminstance.
我将从nminstance的CPP文件中偷取这个函数。
So copy this line and paste it back to this custom moving component that CPP and copy
所以复制这一行并把它粘贴到CPP的自定义移动组件中，然后复制
the name of it, go back to the function.
它的名字，回到这个函数。
So it's going to be you kids math math library.
所以这将是你孩子的数学数学库。
And the function we need is called quad underscore unrotate vector.
而我们需要的这个函数叫做四分法下划线解旋矢量。
So we need to fill in a quarter neon and the vector that we want to unrotate.
所以我们需要填入一个四分之一的霓虹灯和我们要解旋的向量。
So the quarter neon will be our updated component get component quad.
所以，四分之一个氖灯将是我们更新的分量，得到四分量。
And the vector will be our velocity.
而矢量将是我们的速度。
So there's a variable for just there.
所以这里有一个变量。
It's called velocity.
它被称为速度。
And this function here simply needs to return the return result of this function.
这个函数在这里只需要返回这个函数的返回结果。
So I'm going to add a return in front of it.
所以我要在它前面加一个回车。
All right, that's the getter down.
好了，这就是getter了。
Then go back to this nminstance.
然后再回到这个nminstance。
I'm going to create a new variable.
我将创建一个新的变量。
So copy this u property.
所以复制这个u属性。
Paste it in here.
把它粘贴到这里。
It's going to be an F vector.
它将会是一个F向量。
I'm going to call this one climb velocity and create a function for it called get climb
我将把这个称为爬升速度，并为它创建一个函数，叫做get climb
velocity and create a function definition.
速度，并创建一个函数定义。
Place the function at the bottom and call the function first.
把这个函数放在底部，先调用这个函数。
So paste it in here.
所以把它粘贴在这里。
Then go back to it, access the function inside the custom moving component.
然后再回到它，在自定义移动组件里面访问这个函数。
So it's called get unrotate climb velocity and store the result in the variables that
所以它被称为获取解旋爬升速度，并将结果存储在我们刚刚创建的变量中。
we just created.
我们刚刚创建的变量。
So it's called climb velocity.
所以它被称为爬升速度。
All right, that's it.
好了，就这样了。
I'm going to compile first.
我先来编译一下。
I have a successful compile.
我有一个成功的编译。
I'm going to launch my editor.
我将启动我的编辑器。
So go back to my editor.
所以回到我的编辑器。
I think I'm first going to move these two meshes.
我想我首先要移动这两个网格。
So I'm going to delete this ramp and I'm going to move these two meshes to the center a little
所以我将删除这个斜坡，并将这两个网格移到中心位置。
bit and move this place start closer.
然后把这个地方移近。
All right, something like this.
好的，像这样的东西。
Maybe move them to the side.
也许把它们移到旁边去。
All right.
好的。
Then go to this climb system.
然后转到这个爬升系统。
Right mouse button click.
鼠标右键点击。
I'm going to create a blend space.
我将创建一个混合空间。
So instead of animation, go to this blend space and select escape mannequin.
因此，代替动画，进入这个混合空间，选择逃跑的人体模型。
I'm going to call this one BS underscore climbed locomotion and double click to open it.
我将把这个称为BS下划线爬行运动，然后双击打开它。
And inside of it, I'm going to click this asset details.
在它里面，我将点击这个资产细节。
So for this horizontal and vertical axis, we'll need to give them the corresponding
所以对于这个水平轴和垂直轴，我们需要给它们相应的
names.
名称。
So the horizontal one, I'm going to name it horizontal climb speed.
因此，在水平轴上，我将命名为水平爬升速度。
And for this minimum asset value, I'm going to change it to negative 100.
对于这个最小资产值，我将把它改为负100。
So if it's positive 100, we are moving to the right.
因此，如果它是正100，我们就向右移动。
If it's negative, we are moving to the left.
如果它是负的，我们就向左移动。
And for this vertical axis, I'm going to call it vertical climb speed.
对于这个垂直轴，我将把它称为垂直爬升速度。
And for this minimum value, change it to negative 100.
对于这个最小值，把它改为负100。
So this value here should be the same as your max climb speed.
所以这里的数值应该与你的最大爬升速度相同。
If you set yours differently, make sure you catered that in here.
如果你的设置不同，请确保你在这里满足这个要求。
All right, first thing I'm going to drag in the idle animation.
好的，首先我要拖入空闲动画。
So in here, I'm going to search climb idle and drag in this climb idle underscore adjusted.
所以在这里，我将搜索爬升空闲，并拖入这个爬升空闲的下划线调整。
So I'm going to hold down shift on my keyboard and drag it inside.
所以我要按住键盘上的shift键，把它拖进去。
So this can help us to snap the animation to the grid.
所以这可以帮助我们将动画固定在网格上。
So place it in here.
所以把它放在这里。
And next thing we'll need the animation for moving up, down, left and right.
而接下来我们需要的是上下左右移动的动画。
So go back to my content browser.
所以回到我的内容浏览器。
Set of animation raw, I'm going to start with this climbing up, so duplicate it, change
一组动画原件，我将从这个爬升开始，所以复制它，把它的名字改为
its name to climbing up underscore adjusted and move it to the adjusted folder.
它的名字改为爬升下划线调整，并把它移到调整后的文件夹。
Select move here and go to this folder.
在这里选择移动，然后进入这个文件夹。
So same as our idle animation, we'll need to adjust the position of it.
所以和我们的空闲动画一样，我们需要调整它的位置。
So I'm going to double click to open it.
所以我要双击来打开它。
Then hold down shift on my keyboard, double click to open this climb idle and click pause.
然后按住键盘上的shift，双击打开这个攀登空闲，点击暂停。
Move to the first frame.
移动到第一帧。
So this is our initial starting position.
所以这是我们最初的起始位置。
And for this climbing up, I'm going to click pause as well.
而对于这个爬升，我也要点击暂停。
Move to the first frame.
移动到第一帧。
And this is its initial position.
这是它的初始位置。
So I think this one is pretty close without climb idle.
所以我认为这个没有爬升空闲的时候是很接近的。
I'm going to test it first to see if we need to make any adjustments.
我打算先测试一下，看看我们是否需要做任何调整。
So I'm going to go back to my blend space and I'm going to add in that climbing up adjusted.
所以我将回到我的混合空间，我将加入调整后的爬升。
So drag it, hold down shift, place it in here.
所以拖动它，按住shift，把它放在这里。
And I'm going to hold down control on my keyboard to preview the animation.
我将按住键盘上的控制键来预览动画。
Press play in here.
在这里按播放键。
Yeah, I think this looks good enough.
是的，我认为这看起来足够好。
All right, I'm going to hit save.
好的，我将点击保存。
And next thing I'm going to go back to my animation blueprint.
接下来我要回到我的动画蓝图中去。
Now instead of climb idle, I'm going to change its name to climbed locomotion and double
现在，我将把它的名字改为爬升运动，而不是爬升空闲，然后双击打开。
click to open it, delete this idle animation.
点击打开它，删除这个空闲动画。
And I'm going to drag in the blend space that we just created.
我将拖入我们刚刚创建的混合空间。
So it'll be this BS underscore climb locomotion.
因此，它将是这个BS下划线攀升运动。
Drag it to here.
把它拖到这里。
Connect it to the result.
把它连接到结果上。
And for this horizontal and vertical climb speed, we can use the variable that we just
对于这个水平和垂直爬升速度，我们可以使用我们刚刚创建的变量
created.
创建的变量。
So I'm going to hold down control, then drag out this climb velocity.
所以我要按住控制键，然后拖出这个爬升速度。
I must button click to split stroke pan.
我必须点击按钮来分割行程平移。
So for this horizontal speed, this will be the velocity y.
所以对于这个水平速度，这将是速度y。
Vertical speed will be this velocity z.
垂直速度将是这个速度z。
And that's pretty much it.
而这就差不多了。
I'm going to press compile, then I'm going to test it.
我将按编译，然后我将测试它。
So press play, go to the surface, press F and try to move up.
所以按播放键，到表面，按F键并尝试向上移动。
So I think I might need to lower this animation a little bit.
所以我想我可能需要把这个动画降低一点。
And now I think it's a bit higher than this idle animation.
而现在我认为它比这个空闲的动画要高一点。
So I'm going to press play again.
所以我准备再按一次播放。
And this time I'm going to go to this surface here so that we'll have more areas to climb.
这次我要去这个表面，这样我们就有更多的地方可以爬了。
I'm going to try lowering down this climb up animation a little bit.
我将尝试把这个爬升动画降低一点。
So go to this animation folder, open adjust it for this climbing up, click pause, move
因此，进入这个动画文件夹，打开调整它的爬升动画，点击暂停，移动到第一帧，选择根手机。
to the first frame, select root phone, and I'm going to drag it down a little bit, something
到第一帧，选择根手机，我要把它往下拖一点，像这样，然后点击添加键。
like this, and click add key.
像这样，然后点击添加键。
Then go inside of my plan space.
然后进入我的计划空间里面。
So go back to my content browser, climb system, open this plan space.
所以回到我的内容浏览器，爬上系统，打开这个计划空间。
Inside of this asset details, for the smoothing time, horizontal axis and vertical axis, I'm
在这个资产细节中，对于平滑时间，水平轴和垂直轴，我将给它们一个值。
going to give both of them a value of 0.1.
我打算给他们两个的值是0.1。
So we'll have a little bit of planning happening.
因此，我们将有一个小的计划发生。
Alright, I'm going to test this again.
好了，我要再次测试这个。
So press play, go to this surface, press F, then try climbing up.
所以按播放，到这个表面，按F，然后试着爬上去。
Alright, something like that.
好吧，类似这样的东西。
I think this already looks good enough.
我想这看起来已经很不错了。
Exit the climb mode, try again.
退出爬升模式，再试一次。
I think I corrected the current result.
我想我纠正了当前的结果。
Alright, now we have climbing up.
好了，现在我们有了向上的爬升。
I like to add in climbing down.
我喜欢加入向下爬升的部分。
So go back to this animation, inside of raw, select this climbing down, press control plus
所以回到这个动画，在raw里面，选择这个向下爬升，按control plus
D to duplicate it, change its name to climbing down underscore adjust it, and move the animation
D来复制它，把它的名字改成爬行下划线调整，然后把这个动画
to the folder.
到文件夹中。
Then I'm going to first double click to open this climb idle, adjust it.
然后我先双击打开这个爬升空闲，调整一下。
Then I'm going to hold down shift on my keyboard, then double click to open this climbing down,
然后我按住键盘上的shift键，然后双击打开这个爬下的动画、
adjust it, and click pause.
调整它，然后点击暂停。
So this is original offset, and this is the original position of our idle.
所以这是原始的偏移量，这是我们空转的原始位置。
So there's quite some offset in between.
所以这中间有相当多的偏移。
We'll need to adjust this one.
我们需要调整这个。
So select its root bone, drag it down, and I'm going to compare with this idle animation.
所以选择它的根骨，把它拖下来，我要和这个空闲动画进行比较。
I think this is still a bit higher.
我觉得这个还是有点高。
Maybe move it down a little bit more to somewhere near here.
也许把它再往下移一点，移到靠近这里的地方。
Then press this L key, yeah, something like that.
然后按这个L键，是的，类似这样的东西。
We can always come back to readjust it.
我们可以随时回来重新调整它。
And go back to this blame space, hold down shift on my keyboard, drag in this climbing
回到这个怪异的空间，按住键盘上的shift键，把这个爬升的东西拖进去
down, place it in here.
下，把它放在这里。
Hold down control on my keyboard to preview them, press play in here.
按住我键盘上的控制键，预览它们，在这里按下播放。
I think this should work.
我想这应该可以了。
Alright, I'm going to test it.
好了，我要去测试一下。
So go back to my level, press play, and press F, try climbing up, try climbing down.
所以回到我的水平，按播放，然后按F，试着爬上去，试着爬下来。
Yeah, something like that.
是的，类似这样。
I think this works really well.
我认为这个效果非常好。
Try climbing down in here.
试试在这里爬下去。
Yeah, looking pretty cool.
是的，看起来非常酷。
Now that we have climbing down and climbing up ready, next thing would be climbing to
现在我们已经准备好爬下和爬上，下一件事是爬到
the left and right.
左边和右边。
And there'll be our challenge today.
这将是我们今天的挑战。
So our challenge is, same as I did, I'd like you to get the unrotated climb velocity in
所以我们的挑战是，和我一样，我想让你得到未经旋转的爬升速度，在
mn instance.
mn实例。
So for that, you might want to set up a getter inside of our custom movement component.
所以为此，你可能想在我们的自定义运动组件中设置一个获取器。
Then try adding in climbing up and down to your animation blueprint.
然后试着在你的动画蓝图中加入向上和向下的爬升。
Once you succeed, try adding in climbing left and right to your animation blueprint.
一旦你成功了，试着在你的动画蓝图中加入向左和向右的爬行。
The process should be the same.
这个过程应该是一样的。
Alright, pause the video now and give this a go or come back if you need help.
好了，现在暂停视频，试试这个，如果你需要帮助再来。
Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
How did that go for you?
你做得怎么样了？
Hopefully that wasn't too hard for you to do.
希望这对你来说不是太难。
Don't worry if you ran into any issues.
如果你遇到了任何问题，不要担心。
Let's look at how it can be done.
让我们看看如何做到这一点。
So I'm going to go back to this raw folder.
所以我将回到这个原始文件夹。
And first I'm going to select this climb right, duplicate it, add the suffix adjusted to it,
首先，我将选择这个攀登的权利，复制它，添加后缀调整它、
and move it to the adjusted folder.
然后把它移到调整后的文件夹中。
Select move here, then double click to open this idle animation, close this climbing down,
选择移动这里，然后双击打开这个空闲的动画，关闭这个爬升、
and hold down shift on my keyboard, double click to open this climb right, and click
按住键盘上的shift键，双击打开这个攀爬的权利，然后点击
pause in here.
暂停在这里。
So this is the original position of this animation, and this is our original position for idle.
所以这是这个动画的原始位置，这也是我们空闲的原始位置。
So this is much higher than the idle one, so I'm going to lower it down a little bit.
所以这个比空闲的要高很多，所以我要把它降低一点。
Select this root bone, drag it down to somewhere near here.
选择这个根骨，把它拖到靠近这里的地方。
I'm going to compare this with this idle.
我要把这个和这个空闲的进行比较。
Alright, I think they are close enough.
好的，我想它们已经足够接近了。
I'm going to try adding in this to our blame space.
我将尝试把这个加入到我们的责备空间。
So select blame space, and I'm going to search for climb right.
因此，选择责备空间，我将搜索爬升的权利。
Hold down shift, then drag this climb right to here.
按住shift键，然后把这个爬升的权利拖到这里。
Hold down control to preview it.
按住控制键来预览它。
So I think this is still too high, and that's because I forgot to add in the key for this
所以我认为这还是太高了，这是因为我忘了添加这个关键的
climb right.
爬升的键。
So select this add key, hit save, go back to blame space, preview it again.
所以选择这个添加键，点击保存，回到责备空间，再次预览它。
Alright, this looks good enough, and I'm going to add in climb left.
好了，这看起来够好了，我要添加到左边的爬升。
So go back to this raw folder, duplicate this climb left, add adjust it to it.
所以回到这个原始文件夹，复制这个攀登左侧，添加调整到它。
Move it to the corresponding folder, hold down shift, double click to open it, close
把它移到相应的文件夹，按住shift，双击打开它，关闭
this climb right, click pause in here, go to the back of it.
这个攀登的右边，点击这里的暂停，转到它的后面。
So we'll need to lower down its position as well.
所以我们也需要降低它的位置。
So select this root bone, move it down to somewhere near here.
所以选择这个根骨，把它移到这里附近的某个地方。
Then click this add key, go inside of blame space, I'm going to search for climbed left.
然后点击这个添加键，到责备空间里面去，我将搜索攀登的左边。
Hold down shift, drag it to the grid.
按住shift键，把它拖到网格上。
Hold down control to preview it.
按住控制键来预览它。
Yeah, something like that.
是的，类似这样的东西。
Alright, hit save, and I'm going to test them.
好了，点击保存，我要去测试它们。
So press play, then go inside of climb state.
所以按下播放键，然后进入攀登状态内部。
I can move up, I can move left, move to the right.
我可以向上移动，可以向左移动，向右移动。
I think the position for climbing left and right is still too high.
我认为向左和向右攀爬的位置还是太高了。
I'm going to lower them down a little bit more.
我要把它们再放低一点。
So go back to this adjust it folder, go back to this climb left, adjust it.
所以回到这个调整它的文件夹，回到这个向左爬，调整它。
I'm going to lower it down a little bit to somewhere near here.
我要把它降低一点，到接近这里的地方。
And click add key, and I'm going to do the same thing to this climb right.
然后点击 "添加 "键，我将对这个攀岩的右边做同样的事情。
So hold down shift, double click to open it, click pause, select the root bone, lower it
所以按住shift键，双击打开它，点击暂停，选择根部的骨头，降低它，点击添加键。
down, click add key.
下来，点击添加键。
Alright, I'm going to test them again.
好了，我要再次测试它们。
So press play, and try climbing up, climbing to the left, climbing to the right.
所以按播放，并尝试向上爬，向左爬，向右爬。
Yeah, I think this time they are close enough.
是的，我想这次它们足够接近了。
But the blending between the idle and the horizontal animations is still too long.
但是空闲和水平动画之间的融合还是太长了。
So I'm going to go back to my blend space.
所以我准备回到我的混合空间。
For this horizontal axis, I'm going to lower it down to zero.
对于这个水平轴，我将把它降低到零。
And I'm going to see what this feels like.
我想看看这是什么感觉。
So press play again.
所以再次按下播放键。
And climbing up, move to the left, move to the right.
向上爬，向左移动，向右移动。
And just like so.
就像这样。
I think this will do for now.
我想现在这样就可以了。
We can always come back to adjust it later if we need.
如果我们需要，我们可以随时回来调整。
And just like that, we have our climb locomotion.
就这样，我们有了我们的爬升运动。
How cool is that?
这多酷啊？
And don't worry about the hand and feet placement.
不要担心手和脚的位置问题。
We are going to fix that later using control rig.
我们将在以后使用控制装置来解决这个问题。
In this lecture, we successfully set up the climb locomotion for our character.
在这节课中，我们成功地为我们的角色设置了爬升运动。
And starting from next lecture, we will look into how we can add in more features to it.
从下一节课开始，我们将研究如何在其中加入更多的功能。
Well done.
做得好。
I will see you in the next lecture.
我们将在下一讲中再见。
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
[BLANK_AUDIO]